Guide to the Right Wing Pamphlet collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1937-2010; Accession 2016-M-017; 1.58; (3 boxes)
  - Rand, Ayn, "What Is Capitalism?", Late 1960s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Reprint of two-part series in The Objectivist, November-December 1965.
  - Read, Leonard E., "ABC's of Freedom", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Republican National Committee, Women's Division, "Women in the Public Service; A Series of Surveys on Women in Public Office", 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Blue printed folder containing ten packets and leaflets, complete according to the table of contents on the cover, on issues such as women in congress, women at various levels of local government, participation in Republican conventions, etc.
  - Saunders, Carol, "The Communist Conspiracy: How You Can Fight It", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    41 page pamphlet was printed for the edification of personnel at General Motors.
  - Shelton, Judy, "A Guide to Sound Money", 2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    23 page pamphlet is based on the ideas of F.A. Hayek.
  - Smith, Bradley R., "Confessions of a Holocaust Revisionist, Part One", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    This second (enlarged) edition contains a mixture of autobiographical musings and arguments that the Holocaust was a hoax. No Part Two has been published.
  - Smith, William J., "Climax of Civilization: World Conquest by Communism?", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Smith, William J., "The Pope Talks about Labor Relations", 1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Springer, Harvey H., "Communism Out to Take America and Other Sermons", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Cover illustration is a cartoon of a menacing cloud blazoned with hammer and sickle looming over a Western wagon train scene.
  - Support Your Local Police Committees, Belmont, Massachusetts and Phoenix, Arizona, Leaflets, Circa 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    The Committees were connected to the John Birch Society. Leaflets, urging support for local police, turn the phrase "police brutality" on its head to argue that police are brutalized daily on the job. One, a four-panel brochure on omnibus police control reprinted from the John Birch Society's "Review of the News," argues that federal troops sent into the South have no community ties and are controlled entirely by Washington.
  - Tax Rebellion Committee, "Call "Urgent Message" 213-387-2351. Stop Withholding", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Six page document argues that the IRS is unconstitutional and provides dubious legal advice and sample forms for pressing your claim against the government. Title refers to a hotline for listening to relevant recorded messages.
  - Tenney, Jack B., "Zionist Network: A Tenney Report", 1970s (Box 2, Folder 23)
    this is an anti-Semitic, anti-Communist diatribe by a leading California state senator with an introduction by Franklin Hichborn.
  - "Think! Workers - Think! EPIC. Easy Pickings in California. Welcome to California all you Reds," handbill, Circa 1934 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    This was issued in the names of "Lea Harvey Lamborn and nine others murdered by the Mooney bomb," noting that Lamborn was a member of the Typographical Union, and includes q Quotes from Upton Sinclair and Tom Mooney on revolutionary themes, followed by a declaration, "Yours for the revolution AGAINST their revolution."
  - "UN-American BONDS", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Elaborate rightist humor presents a reasonably good visual parody of a fiscal bond, Untied Nations dis-Organization Fabian Enslavement BONDS, which lists allegedly un-American organizations, United Nations officials from Soviet bloc countries, and other evidence of the Communist/Satanic plot to enslave America. It fFeatures an inset cartoon of the UN building casting its shadow over Congress, which is flying the US flag upside-down.
  - Unemployed Citizens Non-Partisan League, Disorganized state of Sinclaria parody dollar bill, Circa 1934 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Front displays text reading "This certifies that (we hope) there has been deposited in The Disorganized State of Sinclaria One Yellow Carrot payable to the bearer under protest" and a caricature of 'Uppy' [Upton Sinclair] in center, signed by "O.U. Phooie". Reverse has "We want jobs for money, no Scrip. Vote for Merriam."
  - United Republicans of America brochures, 1966-circa 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Material consists of a six-panel brochure from 1966 introducing the URA, a group for ultra-conservatives within the Republican Party, asking that they not register for third parties for fear of diluting the conservative vote, together with an undated brochure from after the group's re-organization in 1967, discussing the group's fundraising efforts and lobbying on behalf of conservative candidates.
  - University of New Mexico, The Newspaper, volume 1, #2, 3.5, 5, 7, and 10, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    This anti-communist alternative student paper, calling itself "The University of New Mexico's only independent free news medium" includes (in No. 2) a collection of quotes on women's liberation from students, such gems as this from geology teaching assistant Martin Bregman: "In my opinion, women should be treated exactly as equals until they prove they deserve to be treated as women." Editors were sympathetic to Young Americans for Freedom and refer to the group's materials in various articles. Later issues reflect libertarian perspective.
  - Virginia Republican Assembly, "Virginia GOP Rules", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Document contains plan of organization and rules for the state party, as amended in 1964
  - Welsh, Francis Ralson, "America's Greatest Peril: The Bolsheviki and the Mooney Case", Circa 1918 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    This is a rRight wing attack on Tom Mooney, the American Federation of LAbor (AFL), the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), the anarchists and the left in general.
  - White Aryan Resistance, Handbill issuing a challenge to white people, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Text includes an "Are you tired of..." list, culminating with "The turning of this once-great White nation into an impoverished banana republic ruled by traitors and criminals, owned by foreign corporations and populated by mongreloids? If so, why not join with the thousands of your White kinsmen and kinswomen of the Third Position who are fighting for White survival?"
  - Winrod, Gerald B., Handbills and ephemera, most related to the Supreme Court, 1937, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)